Scooby Goes Hollywood is a animation, comedy, tv
movie film directed by Ray Patterson.
Shaggy and Scooby-Doo quit their Saturday morning TV
series in pursuit of Hollywood stardom.
Shaggy Rogers (voice), played by Casey Kasem.
Scooby-Doo (voice), played by Don Messick.
Fred Jones (voice), played by Frank Welker.
Daphne Blake (voice), played by Heather North.
Velma Dinkley (voice), played by Patricia Stevens.
Kerry / Girl Fan / Executive Secretary (voice), played by Ginny McSwain.
Scooby Goes Hollywood (later released on home video as Scooby-Doo Goes Hollywood) is a 1979 animated
television special starring the cast of Hanna-Barbera's Saturday-morning cartoon series Scooby-Doo.
It was originally broadcast on ABC on December 23, 1979 to
celebrate the 10th anniversary of the franchise.
A musical-based parody of both the Scooby-Doo formula and of Hollywood in general, the story line centered on Shaggy convincing Scooby that both of them deserve better than being stars in what he considers a low-class Saturday morning show, and attempts to pitch a number of potential prime-time
shows to network executive "C.J." (voiced by Rip Taylor), all of which are parodies of movies and then-popular TV shows which are How The West Was Won, Happy Days, Laverne & Shirley, Superman, The Sound of Music, Saturday Night Fever, Sonny & Cher, The Love Boat, and Charlie's Angels.
Caught in the middle of this ordeal are Fred, Daphne, Velma, and Scooby's loyal Saturday morning fan
base; all of whom convince Scooby to come back to his Saturday morning television show.
The special was first released on VHS by Worldvision Enterprises in the
1980s, and again later by Warner Home Video in 1997.
The special was released on DVD by Warner Bros.
on June 4, 2002.
The special was included as a bonus feature in
the Blu-ray release of Scooby-Doo!
and the Reluctant Werewolf in 2024.
The film explores themes of california, talking dog, hollywood.
The tone is lighthearted.